Currently, we waste about one-third of
everything that's produced, and that's
globally.
Now, I believe this is going to become one
of the biggest issues.
Right now, when they
go to the climate summits, they aren't
talking about food waste, but this is
where we could really make a big
difference. We waste one-third of
everything we produce. In rich countries,
it's because food is so cheap, we can
throw it away, right? Servings are
great big. Go to one of these restaurants,
the platter comes out, it's an amazing
amount of food. You might not eat all of
it. It gets discarded. In poorer
countries, it's because there's no
infrastructure to get the crops out of the
field. It's because there's no
refrigeration, so the stuff spoils. So we
produce one-third more than we really need
right now with food waste. In other words,
we grow enough food to feed everybody.
It's a matter of economics,
infrastructure, and distribution. This is
something that's going to be, I think, a
bigger issue moving forward, and it
wouldn't hurt agriculture to hop on this
issue. When we're being attacked about the
amount of water we use in California's
dairies, or the amount of methane that we
produce, or the amount of diesel that we
burn, maybe we should go right to food
waste and say, yes, but consumer, this is
on you. All we're doing is producing the
food. It's not us that's wasting it.
[music]